<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.fragranceprime.ca/blogs/fragrance-insights.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.fragranceprime.ca/blogs/fragrance-insights"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.fragranceprime.ca/blogs/fragrance-insights.atom"/>
  <title>FragrancePrime - Fragrance Insights</title>
  <updated>2017-10-06T20:15:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>FragrancePrime</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.fragranceprime.ca/blogs/fragrance-insights/what-your-favourite-perfume-is-actually-revealing-about-your-personality</id>
    <published>2017-10-06T20:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-28T23:21:27-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.fragranceprime.ca/blogs/fragrance-insights/what-your-favourite-perfume-is-actually-revealing-about-your-personality"/>
    <title>What your Favourite Perfume is actually revealing about your personality</title>
    <author>
      <name>Dilip Hemlani</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0796/9485/t/24/assets/what-your-favourite-perfume-is-actually-revealing-about-your-personality_8409.jpg?18435974278491905996" alt="" data-original="sexy-woman-lying-on-flowers-PEF2GGJ_2_1024x1024.jpg"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have you ever wondered why the floral scent draws your attention over all the other scents?</span></p>
<p><strong>Just like your clothing, jewellery, and shoes draws your unique style, according to research it has been found that your favourite perfume as well, reveals a lot about your personality. Below is a list of the most popular type of scents and what they reveal about your personality.  </strong></p>
<h2><b>Floral Scents </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Floral blends are the top most popular scents in the perfume world. They reveal freshness and feminism. Ladies wearing floral scents are bright and lively. They tend to show off their pretty dresses, skirts, and high heels because they love being so feminine. They are very elegant, modern, sweet, and confident. They love to be the center of attention, and the party never starts without them. </span></p>
<h2><b>Fresh Scents </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those are the beauties with a sense of humour. If you favour fresh scents, then your fragrances are citrus, green, and cool in personality. They say that you are sporty, energetic, and outgoing. You like to live life to the fullest and infuse your sense of humour everywhere. Nobody is as chilled as you are.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Citrus fragrances explode with zesty lemon, mandarin and grapefruit. They are very light and clean. While green fragrances are crisp, sporty, and confident. They have a sharper edge than any other fragrance group. So if you like to show your own sharp edge away from stereotyping then the green scent is for you. </span></p>
<h2><b>Oriental Scents </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For those who leave the greatest impressions. This group of perfume includes the musk and amber elements. They are warm and intense. The fans of this type tend to be bossy, leaders, and achievers. They are perfectionist and total critics of themselves and others. They tend to be harsh on themselves at times, but it definitely pays back in great achievements. If you happen to be one of the rare individuals of oriental scents, then you are a mysterious person and might have a bit of a daredevil side. </span></p>
<h2><b> Fruity Scents </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you like berries, apples and tropical fruit scent you might get a little surprised at who you are. Fruity scents are sweet, but the truth is that its fans are just the opposite. "They tend to be more irritable, cranky, and pessimistic," says Dr Hirsch. You are very moody and don’t get along with others. You might need to consider changing your attitude before it’s too late. </span></p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.fragranceprime.ca/blogs/fragrance-insights/helpful-hints-for-gentlemen-from-your-cologne-connoisseur</id>
    <published>2017-10-06T20:12:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-28T23:21:32-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.fragranceprime.ca/blogs/fragrance-insights/helpful-hints-for-gentlemen-from-your-cologne-connoisseur"/>
    <title>Helpful hints for gentlemen from your cologne connoisseur</title>
    <author>
      <name>Dilip Hemlani</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">We cannot disagree that today fragrances has become one of the main parts of dress code. It is the invisible part that we cannot see but for sure we can smell and remember forever. A fragrance can become part of our personality, part of who we are and how we like to be perceived by the world. </span></i></p>
<h2><b>Why wear a fragrance?</b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">From making you feel more confident, to seducing a woman and enhancing your mood. Guys you need is to understand the amazing impact a scent can have. The right aroma can create an atmosphere around you that makes you feel like you are on top of the world. Surprisingly more than 80% of men do not wear it on a regular basis because it’s just not part of their social practice. Really guys come on!</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a European study it was shown that fragrance is the number one most powerful factor for women in choosing a man, just the opposite to men who uses visual cues in choosing a woman. So yes, wearing the right cologne will boost your charm and desirability amongst women. </span></i></p>
<h2><b>Dress to impress</b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have all heard it “dress to impress” but gentlemen the smell is the key component of your presence. Dressing accordingly will enhance your image and it can make you feel confident about yourself. However wearing the right scent can just boost that confidence to the next level and create an impression that you are a sharp and put-together man. So now you can be confident that you not only look good but also smell good. </span></i></p>
<p><b><i>Now that we understand why it is important for a man to wear a cologne, let’s take a quick look on the etiquette of wearing it correctly. </i></b></p>
<h2><b>Less is more</b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">We need to understand that cologne is not intended to be our scent, it is meant to enhance our aromas in a gentle way. If you are trying to change your bad odors, don’t try to bathe in it, taking a shower can do you better. Putting too much can be over empowering and unbearable for those around you. Knowing when to stop can be tricky because we cannot smell our self like others do. Cologne is intended to be discovered on you and not loudly announced. So as rule of thumb, one spray is enough, two sprays is the max limit. </span></i></p>
<h2><b>Skipping the spray</b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are certain places where you need to be aware that wearing a perfume or cologne can be inappropriate and annoying for others. For example in an airplane where you are 30000 feet above ground closed up in a cabin with no natural air refreshment. In swimming pools as well, the effect of chlorine on fragrances can create bad odors instead of revitalizing. </span></i></p>
<h2><b>Rules for wearing cologne properly    </b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are certain rules for applying cologne professionally. Random is not good and can create a bad effect and impression. You can avoid such mistakes by learning how to wear it properly. </span></i></p>
<i>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spray fragrance on dry and hot areas of the skin, the heat will help you enhance the scents and last longer. Warmest parts of your body are your chest, neck, wrist, forearm, inner elbow, and shoulder. </span></li>
</i><i>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do not spray on clothes because fragrance is supposed to mix with your skin oils.</span></li>
</i><i>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do not rub on skin as it will make the scent weaker. </span></li>
</i><b>
<li>
<i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t spray a cloud into the air and walk through; this will just make you lose all the scent goodnes</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">s.  </span>
</li>
</b><i>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t hide bad odors of your body with perfume, as matter of fact the reaction of chemicals can react nastily and create even worse odors. </span></li>
</i><br><br>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.fragranceprime.ca/blogs/fragrance-insights/the-importance-and-significance-of-wearing-a-specific-fragrance</id>
    <published>2017-10-06T19:58:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-28T23:21:36-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.fragranceprime.ca/blogs/fragrance-insights/the-importance-and-significance-of-wearing-a-specific-fragrance"/>
    <title>The importance and significance of wearing a specific fragrance</title>
    <author>
      <name>Dilip Hemlani</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is it important to wear a perfume? How does it affect our personal impressions? You must be aware that it not only has an impact on you but also on those around you. Over all, perfumes are intended to create an atmosphere of beauty and seduction.   </span></i></p>
<h2><b>Lasting Impression</b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">For many of us preparing for an event or even just being seen walking on the street, our outfit does not feel complete without the final touches of our favorite perfume spray. It’s part of who we are, and how we like to be perceived by others. For example, a floral based scent boosts your feminism, while an oriental based scent shows that you are resilient and in control. As a matter of fact, people around you will definitely recognize that you’re wearing a perfume and will most probably remember you every time they smell the same scent. It will get attached with you and last in their memory. </span></i></p>
<h2><b>Perfume and skin reaction</b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Choosing your own unique perfume is not just something related to taste, but also our skin reacts differently to scents creating a unique smell owned by you only. The exact bottle of perfume that your friend uses might smell slightly differently on you. You need to be aware that what suits others might not suit you. So if you want to make a good impression, you need to be careful that the scent you smell and like on others actually suits your skin after reaction. </span></i></p>
<h2><b>Mood enhancer</b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scents are scientifically proven to have an effect on our mood. Different scents will have different effects on our mood, and this is the reason why you have to be careful on selecting what actually uplifts your mood, and not the opposite. For example, a vanilla based perfume may help you to keep calm, while a spicy based perfume might make you feel tensioned. Fresh scents might help you keep alert and feel energized which is a typical choice for sport players. Musky scents are very warm and may help you feel romantic and sensual. Floral scents are very pretty and may help you expose your feminism. For a different effect away from mood, wood-based scents help smokers to eliminate smoke odors.   </span></i></p>
<h2><b>Seducing</b></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perfume plays just an equally important role in seduction, like clothes do. This is the reason why we see most perfume advertisements tie their scents with seduction. It is how they position their perfume in the market. Seduction is an approach to creating pleasant human relationships. We seduce each other in many ways, not just sexually as many think. For example a job interview needs an art of seduction different from a date. We can use perfumes to seduce and create that bond we are looking for. </span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conclusion, perfume must be part of us and never be ignored. It gives a message of who we are. It creates a lasting impression, enhances our mood, and plays a key role in seducing others to you.</span></i></p>
]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
